- Are you ready, kids?
- 孩子们，你们准备好了吗？
all:
Aye, aye, Captain!
全部：
是啊是啊，队长！
- I can't hear you.
- 我听不到你说话。
all:
Aye, aye, Captain!
全部：
是啊是啊，队长！
- * Ohh... *
-*哦...*
* Who lives in a pineapple
under the sea? *
*谁住在菠萝里
在海底？ *
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
- * Absorbent and yellow
and porous is he *
- * 吸水性和黄色
他是多孔的*
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
- * If nautical nonsense
be something you wish *
- *如果航海废话
成为你所希望的*
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
- * Then drop on the deck
and flop like a fish *
- * 然后落在甲板上
然后像鱼一样扑通扑通 *
all: SpongeBob SquarePants!
- Ready?
所有：海绵宝宝！
- 准备好？
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
SpongeBob SquarePants!
- SpongeBob
- 海绵宝宝
SquarePants!
方裤！
[laughing]
[笑]
* *
**
[waves crashing]
[海浪拍打]
[retro adventurous music]
【复古冒险音乐】
* *
**
[bubbling]
[冒泡]
[mysterious music]
[神秘的音乐]
- [imitates static] This is
Junior Crime Breaker SpongeBob,
- [模仿静电] 这是
少年破案海绵宝宝，
reporting to
Junior Crime Breaker Patrick.
向
少年破案犯帕特里克。
[imitates static]
There are no signs of crime
[模仿静电]
没有任何犯罪迹象
in front of my house.
Any criminal activity by you?
在我家前面。
您有任何犯罪活动吗？
Over.
[imitates static]
超过。
[模仿静电]
- [imitates static]
- [模仿静电]
Uh...I've got a visual
呃……我有视觉效果
on a old lady tying her shoes.
一位正在系鞋带的老太太。
[whispering]
She's doing the granny knot.
[窃窃私语]
她正在打奶奶结。
- Oh, I'll give you
a granny knot!
-哦，我给你
一个奶奶结！
- [grunts]
All clear!
- [咕哝]
一切都清楚了！
No crime here.
- [chomps]
这里没有犯罪。
- [咀嚼]
[boing]
[嗡嗡声]
- [laughing]
- [笑]
- [imitates static]
Patrick, emergency meeting
- [模仿静电]
帕特里克，紧急会议
at Squidward's house--ASAP!
到章鱼哥家里——尽快！
- [humming]
- Oh, please, Squidward,
- [嗡嗡声]
-哦，求你了，章鱼哥，
don't move away!
You can't leave
别走开！
你不能离开
the neighborhood!
Aw, we were just starting
邻居！
噢，我们才刚刚开始
to get close.
[whimpers]
靠近。
[呜咽]
- [inhales deeply]
I swear,
- [深吸一口气]
我发誓，
I'll haunt your nightmares
if you move away!
我会困扰你的噩梦
如果你搬走！
- I'm not moving away,
you brainless bottom feeders!
- 我不会离开，
你们这些无脑的底层喂食者！
[munching, swallowing]
[咀嚼、吞咽]
I'm just taking
a week's vacation
我只是在拿
一周的假期
away from you morons.
离你们这些白痴远点。
- [squeals]
- [尖叫声]
[whispering]
Thank you.
[窃窃私语]
谢谢你。
[shouts]
[喊叫]
Let me help you carry this.
- No--wait, no!
让我帮你搬运这个。
- 不——等等，不！
- [struggles, shouts]
- [挣扎，喊叫]
Oh--your unmentionables.
- [grumbling angrily]
哦——你的不可告人的事。
- [愤怒地抱怨]
- I won't mention this bra.
- 我不会提到这个胸罩。
- It's not a bra!
It's a pectoral girdle.
- 这不是胸罩！
这是胸带。
I don't care about my clothes.
我不关心我的衣服。
I just wanna get away
from you two.
我只是想离开
来自你们两个。
And while I'm away--
huh...
当我不在的时候——
呵呵...
- [struggling]
- [挣扎]
[squeals quietly]
- [grunts, mumbles]
[小声尖叫]
- [咕哝声，咕哝声]
- [incoherent screaming]
- [语无伦次的尖叫声]
[growls]
[咆哮]
While I am gone,
当我不在的时候，
there will be a paying guest
renting my place.
将会有一位付费客人
租我的地方。
Don't bother him!
别打扰他！
* *
**
[bubbling]
[冒泡]
[wheels screech]
[车轮的尖叫声]
- [imitates static] This is
Junior Crime Breaker SpongeBob
- [模仿静电] 这是
少年破案海绵宝宝
to Junior Crime Breaker Patrick.
少年破案犯帕特里克。
I've got a visual on a cab.
我看到了出租车上的景象。
Can you get a make
on who the passenger is?
你能得到一个品牌吗
乘客是谁？
Over.
[imitates static]
超过。
[模仿静电]
- [imitates static]
I can't see anything
- [模仿静电]
我什么也看不见
through these unmentionables.
[imitates static]
通过这些不可告人的事情。
[模仿静电]
announcer: Who's
this tacky tourist
播音员：谁
这个俗气的游客
turning up in a taxi?
出现在出租车上？
Why, it's none other than
that mortal enemy
为什么，不是别人，正是
那个死敌
of Mermaid Man
and Barnacle Boy,
人鱼男的
和藤壶男孩，
the evil Man Ray!
邪恶的曼·雷！
- Hey, dude, keep it down.
=> - 嘿，伙计，小声点。
I'm not doing
any evil this week.
我没有做
本周有任何邪恶的事情发生。
I'm on vacation!
我在度假！
announcer: Really?
播音员：真的吗？
- Yes, really.
- 是的，真的。
[humming cheerily]
[欢快地哼唱]
[Patrick and SpongeBob panting]
[帕特里克和海绵宝宝气喘吁吁]
- Aw, he went inside!
- 噢，他进去了！
Patrick, wouldn't it be great
to have another friend
帕特里克，这不是很棒吗
多一个朋友
who can join
our Junior Crime Breakers?
谁可以加入
我们的少年犯罪破坏者？
Ooh, I gotta get a look at him!
- [squealing quietly]
噢，我得看看他！
- [小声尖叫]
We can blast him out.
- No, no!
我们可以把他轰出去。
- 不，不！
Squidward said
not to bother the man.
章鱼哥说
不要去打扰那个男人。
- [grunts]
- So, we gotta be sneaky.
- [咕哝]
- 所以，我们必须偷偷摸摸。
[sneaky music]
[偷偷摸摸的音乐]
[stifles shout]
Shh!
[窒息喊叫]
嘘！
He must've gone upstairs.
他肯定已经上楼了。
[both panting]
[两人都气喘吁吁]
- Well, how do we get up there?
- 那么，我们怎么上去呢？
- "Eye" have just the thing!
——“眼”有正事！
[giggles]
[咯咯笑]
Ow!
噢！
[grunts, shouts]
[咕哝声，喊叫声]
- [snoring]
- [打鼾]
[shivers]
Oh, it's getting chilly.
[发抖]
哦，天气变冷了。
- Ow!
[groans weakly]
- 噢！
[微弱地呻吟]
D'ow!
哎哟！
Ow!
噢！
Oof!
钱币！
[yelps]
Ow.
[尖叫声]
噢。
[bubbling]
[冒泡]
[doorbell rings]
Now, I know Squidward said
[门铃响]
现在，我知道章鱼哥说过
not to bother his guest,
不打扰他的客人，
but there's nothing wrong
但没有什么问题
with a
welcome-to-the-neighborhood pie.
与一个
欢迎来到邻居馅饼。
[giggling squeal]
[咯咯地尖叫]
- Oh!
May I help you?
- 哦！
我可以帮你吗？
I was just finishing up
in the bathroom.
我刚刚完成
在浴室里。
- Hello.
Welcome to the neighborhood!
- 你好。
欢迎来到邻居！
- Don't mind us.
- Wha...
- 别介意我们。
- 世界卫生大会...
Hmm!
唔！
- [grunts heavily]
- [重重地咕哝]
- Is this sand?
- 这是沙子吗？
- Hamper sand--
from my hamper.
- 礼篮沙--
从我的篮子里。
- [quietly]
Ugh!
- [安静地]
呃！
- Yeah, stranger,
- 是的，陌生人，
we got a nice little town here--
我们这里有一个漂亮的小镇——
thanks to
the Junior Crime Breakers.
感谢
少年犯罪破坏者。
And we're always looking
for new members.
我们一直在寻找
对于新会员。
You look pretty fit.
- SpongeBob.
你看起来很健康。
- 海绵宝宝。
He's not putting out
any snacks for us.
他没有推出
任何零食给我们。
- Oh, sorry!
How rude of me.
- 哦，对不起！
我真粗鲁。
Hmm...ooh!
嗯……哦！
All I have is this pie.
我只有这个馅饼。
- Don't mind if I do.
- 如果我这样做的话，请不要介意。
[gobbling]
[狼吞虎咽]
[munching]
[咀嚼]
- Eh--if you'll excuse me,
I'll finish up in the bathroom.
- 呃--请原谅我，
我会在浴室里完成。
- [pants]
- [裤子]
He's all outta snacks!
Let's go.
他已经没有零食了！
我们走吧。
- But, Patrick, we haven't
asked him to join
- 但是，帕特里克，我们还没有
请他加入
the Junior Crime Breakers yet.
少年犯罪破坏者还没有。
Hello?
We were wondering if
你好？
我们想知道是否
you'd like to--
[screams]
你想——
[尖叫声]
[panting franticly]
[疯狂地喘气]
[stuttering]
[结巴]
- [humming]
- [嗡嗡声]
- [quietly]
Evil villain Man Ray.
- [安静地]
邪恶的恶棍曼·雷。
[ominous trumpet tune]
[不祥的喇叭曲]
- Now, what were you saying?
- 现在，你在说什么？
Hmm?
What?
唔？
什么？
Hmm?
唔？
Hmm.
唔。
[bubbling]
[冒泡]
[both panting]
[两人都气喘吁吁]
- Mermaid Man!
It's Man Ray!
- 美人鱼男人！
是曼·雷！
He's right inside
Squidward's...place.
他就在里面
章鱼哥的……地方。
[dramatic music]
[戏剧音乐]
Too late.
Man Ray must've gotten to them.
为时已晚。
曼雷肯定已经找到他们了。
- [whimpering]
- [呜咽]
Mermaid Man and Barnacle Boy
ice pops!
美人鱼人和藤壶男孩
冰棒！
They finally made them!
他们终于成功了！
[slurping, glass squeaking]
- Wait a minute, Patrick.
[发出声音，玻璃吱吱作响]
- 等一下，帕特里克。
We're both wrong!
It says right here in issue 55.
我们都错了！
就在第 55 期这里说的。
Mermaid Man and Barnacle Boy
are just taking
美人鱼人和藤壶男孩
正在采取
their cryonic nap.
But when they wake up in a week,
他们的冷冻小睡。
但当他们一周后醒来时，
they'll be weak
for a week!
他们会很弱
一个星期！
[shouts happily]
[高兴地大喊]
Patrick, do you know
what this means?
帕特里克，你知道吗
这意味着什么？
- I'll have to wait a week
for my Mermaid Man ice pop?
-我得等一个星期
给我的美人鱼人冰棒？
- Yes and no.
It means that
- 是和不是。
这意味着
you and I will have to be
Mermaid Man and Barnacle Boy,
你和我必须
美人鱼人和藤壶男孩，
and stop Man Ray's vacation
of...
并停止曼雷的假期
的...
[thunder claps]
Evil!
[雷鸣般的掌声]
邪恶！
[together]
By the power of Neptune,
[一起]
借助海王星的力量，
Mermaid Pants
and Barnacle Star unite!
人鱼裤
和藤壶星联合起来！
[victorious music]
[胜利的音乐]
- [giggling]
- [咯咯笑]
[both grunting]
[两人都咕哝着]
- [slurping]
- Patrick, is that...
- [发出声音]
- 帕特里克，那是……
I couldn't wait a week!
我等了一个星期都等不及了！
[both grunting]
[两人都咕哝着]
Yow!
- [shouting]
哟！
- [喊叫]
- [struggling]
- [growling]
- [挣扎]
- [咆哮]
Ah-ah-ah--
啊啊啊啊——
[sobbing]
[抽泣]
- [snoring]
- [打鼾]
[trash cans rattling]
[垃圾桶嘎嘎作响]
- Good thing I'm so stealthy,
- 还好我很隐秘
huh, Mermaid Pants?
嗯，美人鱼裤？
Ah!
The stealth!
啊!
隐身！
- [grunting]
- [咕哝]
[metal crashing]
[金属碰撞]
- Huh?
- 啊？
Hmm?
唔？
Hmm!
唔！
[both grunting quietly]
[两人都低声咕哝]
- Ow!
- 噢！
[both shouting menacingly]
[两人都威胁地喊道]
- [shouts]
- [喊叫]
* *
**
[debris clatters]
- Intruders?
[碎片碰撞声]
- 入侵者？
Mm-hmm...
I've got to call the cops.
嗯嗯...
我得报警。
What am I doing?
我在做什么？
Villains don't call the police!
坏人不报警！
[sighs]
I didn't think to bring
[叹气]
没想到要带
any evil super-weapons
on vacation!
任何邪恶的超级武器
度假了！
I'm unarmed!
我手无寸铁！
Huh?
啊？
- Who'da thunk that Squidward
would be stockpiling
- 谁会想到那个章鱼哥
会囤积的
such a huge arsenal
of evil super-weapons?
如此庞大的军火库
邪恶的超级武器？
* *
**
So stale, yet so deadly.
如此陈腐，却又如此致命。
[whimpering nervously]
[紧张地呜咽]
[shouts, thuds]
[喊叫声，重击声]
I got my weapon!
我拿到武器了！
- [grunting approvingly]
- [赞同地咕哝]
[both singing, shouting]
[两人都唱着、喊着]
- * Dum-dah-dah *
- * 达姆达达 *
- Mermaid Man and Barnacle Boy?
- 美人鱼人和藤壶男孩？
I knew you guys were old,
我就知道你们都老了
but I had no idea you mutated.
- Surrender, Man Ray!
但我不知道你变异了。
- 投降，曼·雷！
- I'm on holiday.
- 我正在度假。
- Yeah, an evil holiday!
- 是的，一个邪恶的假期！
- Prepare to be framed!
[grunts]
- 准备好被陷害吧！
[咕哝]
- [grunts]
- [咕哝]
[vase shatters]
[花瓶碎裂]
announcer: Vase vaporized!
播音员：花瓶蒸发了！
[adventurous music]
[冒险音乐]
- Here's a dessert
that's sure to hurt!
- 这是一份甜点
那肯定会受伤！
[shouts]
[喊叫]
- Huh?
[shouts]
- 啊？
[喊叫]
* *
**
announcer: Figurines fractured!
播音员：雕像断裂了！
[cookies ricocheting]
- [grunts]
[饼干弹跳]
- [咕哝]
[both whimpering]
[两人都呜咽]
[both panting fearfully]
[两人都惊恐地喘着气]
[shouting]
[喊叫]
- [growling]
- [shouting]
- [咆哮]
- [喊叫]
No, no, no, no,
不，不，不，不，
no!
不！
[wailing]
[哀号]
- All right, Man Ray.
- 好吧，曼雷。
I will snare you
in my "clara-net"!
我会网罗你
在我的“clara-net”中！
[sour clarinet notes]
[酸单簧管音符]
- [grunts, shouts]
Oof!
- [咕哝声，喊叫声]
噢！
- [inhales purposefully]
- [有目的地吸气]
Uh...
呃...
I can't think of anything!
我什么也想不出来！
[shouting]
[喊叫]
- [muffled grunting]
- [低沉的咕哝声]
[both shout]
[两人大喊]
announcer: Table toppled!
播音员：桌子翻倒了！
[all shouting,
thunder booms]
[大家都喊着，
雷霆轰鸣]
[planks clatter]
[木板碰撞声]
[Patrick and SpongeBob shouting]
[帕特里克和海绵宝宝大喊]
- I just wanted a vacation!
- 我只是想要一个假期！
- Evil never takes a vacation!
- 邪恶永远不会休假！
- [stammers]
Did you just make that up?
- [结巴]
这是你刚刚编出来的吗？
Because that sounds pretty good.
因为这听起来不错。
Do you mind if
I use it sometime?
你介意吗
我有时用它？
- Help yourself, Man Ray.
- 救救自己吧，曼雷。
- Yeah, help yourself to pain!
- 是的，帮助自己止痛！
[thunder clapping]
[雷鸣般的掌声]
* *
**
- [groans]
Why did I ever bother
- [呻吟]
我为什么要费心
trying to be normal?
试图变得正常？
I am Man Ray!
我是曼·雷！
Feel my evil wrath!
感受我邪恶的愤怒吧！
[thunder booms]
[雷霆轰鸣]
[all growling]
[全都咆哮]
[all yelping]
[全都尖叫]
[all shouting]
[大家大喊]
[phone ringing]
- Huh?
[电话铃声]
- 啊？
Hold on.
I should get this.
坚持，稍等。
我应该得到这个。
Hello?
- Hello, Man Ray?
你好？
- 你好，曼·雷？
The weather changed my plans.
I'm coming home.
天气改变了我的计划。
我要回家了。
[grunts]
Not to worry, though.
[咕哝]
不过不用担心。
You'll get a full refund
on the rent,
您将获得全额退款
在租金上，
so long as there's no damage
to my place.
只要没有损坏
到我的地方。
[dial tone]
Hello?
[拨号音]
你好？
- [laughs evilly]
- [邪恶地笑]
That idiot octopus doesn't know
那只白痴章鱼不知道
I gave him a phony check!
我给了他一张假支票！
[shouts victoriously]
[胜利的呼喊]
You were right about me
after all, dopey duo.
你对我的看法是对的
毕竟，愚蠢的二人组。
Evil never takes a vacation!
邪恶永远不会休假！
- Ooh!
Definitely sounds
- 哦！
绝对听起来
a lot cooler
when he says it.
凉爽多了
当他这么说的时候。
[horn honking]
- Ah, here's my Scuber.
[喇叭鸣响]
- 啊，这是我的 Scuber。
[cheery tune]
[欢快的曲调]
[grunts]
[咕哝]
[cackles]
[咯咯笑]
- Maybe one day
Man Ray will reform
- 也许有一天
曼雷将改革
and join
the Junior Crime Breakers.
并加入
少年犯罪破坏者。
[boing]
[嗡嗡声]
Huh?
啊？
- Man, he really
trashed this place.
- 伙计，他真的
毁掉了这个地方。
- Okay, Barnacle Star!
Let's be super good
- 好吧，藤壶星！
让我们变得超级优秀
and glue all
of Squidward's stuff
并粘合所有
章鱼哥的东西
back together!
- Well, how do we do that?
一起回来！
- 那么，我们该怎么做呢？
- [chuckling] Oh, Patrick,
it's right here
- [咯咯笑]哦，帕特里克，
就在这里
in issue 14.
[slurps]
在第 14 期。
[啜饮]
We have super saliva!
我们口水超级多！
[giggling]
[咯咯笑]
[slurping]
[发出声音]
- Ow!
- 噢！
- [humming]
- [嗡嗡声]
[slurping, humming]
[发出声音，哼哼]
* *
**
[splashing]
[溅]
- Hello?
- 你好？
[shimmering tones
and harp music]
[闪烁的色调
和竖琴音乐]
- Oh, looks like
my guest left already.
- 哦，看起来像
我的客人已经离开了。
[sighs contentedly]
Home sweet...
[满足地叹气]
回家甜...
[shouting]
[喊叫]
[groaning]
Home.
[呻吟]
回家。